

Quin Hsieh | Quiny

Data Scientist | Project Manager

Profile

Data scientist with excellent communication and programming skills. Built problem solving experience as data analyst & project manager. Expertise in data mining and cross-unit communication, proposing valuable solutions. Highly motivated self-learner with a strong mindset to collaborate multi-disciplinarily.

Employment History

Data Scientist | Associate Researcher at CECI, Taipei

Sep 2020 — Currently

- Design large and expansive scale, implement distributed computing of data
- Processing, cleansing, verifying and optimizing the data process pipeline used for analysis.
- Selecting features, building and optimizing classifiers using machine learning techniques.
- Analyze large amounts of data to discover trends and patterns.
- Build predictive models and machine learning algorithms.
- Present information using data visualization techniques.
- Collaborate with other team to build supervised and unsupervised learning capabilities with prediction, early alerting, and prescriptive recommendations.

Data Scientist | Project Manager at TAITRA, Taipei

June 2019 — Sep 2020

- Data analysis of global industrial potential market, and reference for forecasting target market expansion.
- Modeled the growth rate prediction of imports and exports of various countries, and estimated the trends of international trade situation.
- Preprocessing and analysis of big data, developed and established of statistical models.
- Planned and designed an automated platform of data analysis.

Data Analyst | Project Manager at Luxgen Motor Co., Ltd., Taipei

April 2018 — May 2019

- SAS Warranty Analysis system for market compensation analysis.
- Planned the road test for the development of the Outsider (PSQC) of the new car, and analyzed the concentration trend based on the problems.
- Vehicle Dependability Study project quality analysis.
- Analyzed the trend forecast of market vehicle problems.
- Developed vehicle internet system and built data database.
- Managed the quality status of each node of vehicle models and the progress of the quality assurance plan.

Data Analyst | Project Manager at HAITEC Automobile Technical Center, Taipei

Details

+886 910 222 538 koala750226@gmail.com

Links

Side project: COVID-19
Dashboard

Side project: LUXGEN

Dashboard

Side project: Forecasting Platform

Side project: Taiwan Mountain
Map

Skills

Interpersonal Communication

Analytical Thinking Skills

Industry Trends Forecasting

Market Assessment

Data Visualization Skills

Analytical and Problem-Solving sk

R Programming

Python Programming

SAS Programming

Languages

Chinese

English

Japanese

Hobbies

Mountaineering, jogging, swimming and camping.

- Developed and analyzed short, medium and long-term KPI of company quality goals and trends.
- Initial Quality Study project quality analysis.
- Promoted Six Sigma and DFSS activities of quality improvement.
- Planned and published Six Sigma, DFSS standard processes and procedures documents.
- Applied Quality Function Deployment and Monte Carlo Simulation to promote training statistical analysis of products.

Quality Assurance Engineer at Unimicron Technology Co., Ltd., Taoyuan

September 2012 — August 2013

- Raw material and product quality control and monitoring.
- Control of mass production product quality inspection workflow.
- Reliability & failure analysis report writing and compilation.
- Product reliability test and problem analysis.
- Data collection and trend analysis of quality data database.
- Analysis of product quality issues and 8D report writing.

Education

Master of Applied Mathematics, National Dong Hwa University, Hualien

September 2009 — June 2011

- Thesis title: "Goodness of Fit Tests for GEE Models with Correlated Ordinal Data". Extending the statistics to general marginal regression models with correlated ordinal data, including its analysis and simulation for assessing the goodness of fitted marginal models.
- Advisor: Dr. Wei-Hsiung, CHAO, NDHU
- Main subjects: Biostatistics, Advanced Probability theory, Cryptocurrencies
 & Blockchain and Programming.

Bachelor of Statistics, Tunghai University, Taichung

September 2004 — June 2009

Main subjects: Statistics, Actuarial Mathematics, Risk Management,
 Financial Management, Probability Theory and Game Theory.